malaymail.com 2018-05-15

# Privacy Policy | Malay Mail

Please note that Malay Mail’s website, inclusive of other platforms (“Malay Mail”) reserves the right to revise this privacy policy at any time by posting an update on this website. Please ensure that you check this website from time to time to review the current privacy policy against any preferences you may have indicated. 

### What is this privacy policy for?

Malay Mail is determined to protect your privacy. It is very important to us that you should be able to browse the website without having to compromise your privacy unacceptably. 

Knowing something about our users is necessary to ensure that our service is continually improved. We need to build an accurate picture of the needs and wishes of our users, and to be able to communicate with you. That enables us to offer a service that is relevant and truly interactive, which is what our users expect. It also helps us to maintain the greatest possible free-to-user access to the website. 

### What information will you collect about me?

We may ask you to provide personal information on a voluntary basis in order to get a clearer picture of our users. It is then entirely up to you whether you are happy to give us this information. 

For example, in the course of certain activities such as commenting on the website, entering competitions, promotions, and other offers, or submitting content to the website, you will be asked to give some personal details (for example, email address, name, postcode or year of birth). 

You may also choose to email us or make contact with us in other ways. Such contact gives us information about you. We endeavour to explain to you why we would like this information and what we do with it at each stage. 

If you have any financial dealings, for instance if you make purchases with our trading partners on co-branded websites, the information you submit will be disclosed to us and to relevant third parties, for example suppliers of goods and services and our web service providers. 

Please do not submit your personal information to us if you do not want us to collect it. Malay Mail automatically collects data about our users' browsing actions and patterns. This is aggregate data and does not identify any individual. Malay Mail does this using web beacons or cookies through a number of carefully selected, trusted third parties. 

Malay Mail also collects information from social media activity such as when you "like" the website, share content or follow Malay Mail on social media platforms. When you sign in to the website using social media you grant permission to the social network to share your user details. Depending on the network, this will include basic account information such as name, email address, date of birth, and any other details you choose to share according to your particular social media account settings. 

### How will this information be used?

We use the aggregate audience details (where no individual is identifiable) to help us improve our understanding of our users and what they want. We may use it to assist us in arranging more personalised advertising, commercial opportunities, and competitions which help us keep the website free for you to enjoy. 

We also use this information to ensure we provide the best possible content, tailoring where we can to our users interests. It also helps us develop the website and audit its use. 

The information about you as an identifiable individual, including contact details, may be used in a number of ways, including: 

  * Verifying your identity (for example when you return to the website) 
  * Personalising your visits to the website and developing the design and style of the website to improve the services provided to you 
  * Informing you about the latest changes to the website, or products, services or promotional offers that you might find interesting 
  * Dealing with, and responding to you about, a comment you have submitted for and other such user generated content facilitie 
  * Enabling you to share our content with others using social media or email 
  * Informing you if you have been successful in any website competitions or promotions 
  * Compiling customer reviews 
  * Conducting market research 

### Will I receive spam?

We will not send you any unsolicited marketing. 

Please note that registered users may receive important information about Malay Mail (such as changes to Malay Mail’s service or other administrative matters). As a registered user, this is not spam. 

### How long do you keep my personal information for?

We will keep your information only for as long as it is relevant and useful for the purpose for which it was originally collected. 

### What security measures do you use?

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the Internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access. 

### Who will you share my personal information with?

By using the website, you agree that we may disclose your personal information to any company within the Malay Mail group of companies. 

Advertisers and advertising networks sometimes require data to select and serve relevant advertisements to you and others. However, we do not disclose information about identifiable individuals to advertisers, but we may provide them with aggregate information about our users (for example, we may inform them that 500 men aged under 30 have clicked on their advertisement on any given day). 

We reserve the right to disclose your personal information to comply with applicable laws (such as the Personal Data Protection Act 2010) and government or regulatory bodies' lawful requests for information. 

We may also have to release information (which could include the contents of email communications between any persons) because of a legal requirement on us or pursuant to a court order. 

We may transfer, sell or assign any of the information described in this policy to third parties as a result of a sale, merger, consolidation, change of control, transfer of assets or reorganisation of our business. 

### Will my data be sent overseas?

The Internet does not recognise national boundaries. Services on the Internet are accessible globally, so collection and transmission of personal data is not always confined to one country. 

You should be aware that by using the website and those of our partners or any website we link through to, your personal data may be processed in or transferred to other countries, and you agree to your personal data being transferred or processed in this way. 

### What do I do if I am not happy for you to share information about me with others?

You may not wish us to share personal details about yourself with third parties outside Malay Mail, or to use your information in the other ways we have described in this privacy policy. 

### User generated content

User generated content facilities, such as comments, videos, and etc, are made available to users of the website and registered users can provide content for and participate in these facilities. Any information that is disclosed in these areas of our website becomes public information and you should always be careful when deciding to disclose your personal information. 

### Email a friend and share this article facilities

When you use these facilities and provide us with personal data (for example, name and email address) of a third party, please ensure that you have their consent before giving us their details. 

### Other Websites

The website may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of advertisers and other third parties. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites. 

* * *
